questions=[{
    question:"Who of the following won the 'Man of the Match' Award in the 1983 World Cup final?",
    options:"Mohinder Amarnath,Kapil Dev,Sunil Gavaskar,K Shrikanth",
    answer:"Mohinder Amarnath",
    answerDescriprion:"Mohinder Amarnath was awarded with MoM for his contribution of 26 runs and 3 wickets"
},
{
    question:"Who among the following cricketer was the first to be given out by the 3rd empire?",
    options:"Ricky Ponting,Sachin Tendulkar,MS Dhoni,Rahul Dravid",
    answer:"Sachin Tendulkar",
    answerDescriprion:"Sachin Tendulkar, Karl Liebenberg was the third umpire with Cyril Mitchley the on-field umpire"
},
{
    question:"First cricket world cup final was played between?",
    options:"West Indies vs England,West Indies vs Australia,South Africa vs Austrlia,South Africa vs West Indies",
    answer:"West Indies vs Australia",
    answerDescriprion:"Correct answer is West Indies vs Australia, West Indies won by 17 runs"
},
{
    question:"In which year, World Cup were innings reduced from 60 to 50 overs?",
    options:"1975,1983,1987,1995",
    answer:"1987",
    answerDescriprion:"1987 world cup was hosted by India and Pakistan, in which each innings had 50 overs"
},
{
    question:"Which country hosted the first t20 worldcup",
    options:"England,Australia,Newzeland,South Africa",
    answer:"South Africa",
    answerDescriprion:"South Africa hosted first t20 world cup in 2007, which was won by India"
},
{
    question:"What is the highest Innings score in international test cricket?",
    options:"782/8,659/4,952/6,994/10",
    answer:"952/6",
    answerDescriprion:"SriL Lanka holds the highest score in an test innings with a score of 952/6"
},
{
    question:"Which of the following cricketer holds the record of most number of Man of the match award in ODI?",
    options:"Jaque Kallis,Muthaiya Murlidharan,Sachin Tendulkar,Adam Gilchrist",
    answer:"Sachin Tendulkar",
    answerDescriprion:"In ODI matches Sachin Tendulkar holds the record for the highest number of man of the match awards, with 62 in 463 matches."
},
{
    question:"which of the following batsman holds the record for fastest test cricket century",
    options:"Cris Gayle,Brando McCullum,Brian Lara,Andrew Symonds",
    answer:"Brando McCullum",
    answerDescriprion:"Brando McCulum took just 54 balls to reach the milestone in a match against Australia"
},
{
    question:"Who was the first cricketer to score a century for india in ODI",
    options:"Lala Amarnath,Kapil Dev,Sunil Gavaskar,Mohinder Amarnath",
    answer:"Kapil Dev",
    answerDescriprion:"Kapil Dev was the first Indian to score an ODI hundred, after he hit 175*(138) against Zimbabwe during the 1983 World Cup"
},
{
    question:"In which year IPL was hostel outside India for the first time?",
    options:"2010,2009,2008,2012",
    answer:"2009",
    answerDescriprion:"In year 2009, IPL was hosted in South Africa"
},
{
    question:"Who holds the record of longest six in international cricket",
    options:"Brandon McCullum,Cris Gayle,Shahid Afridi,Rohit Sharma",
    answer:"Shahid Afridi",
    answerDescriprion:"Shahid Afridi hit a 153m long six against South Africa in year 2013"
},
{
    question:"Against which team, Sachin Tendulkar scored a double-ton in ODI?",
    options:"Bangladesh,South Africa,England,Pakistan",
    answer:"South Africa",
    answerDescriprion:"Master Blaster achieved the feat against South Africa at the Captain Roop Singh Stadium, Gwalior. He played an unbeaten knock of 200 off just 147 balls with the help of 25 fours and 3 sixes."
}]